Guide to the Hanover Royal Music Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Music and Books About Music, 1714-1951; Series I; 13.33; (615 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I, General Music and Books About Music, is organized by composer or author name, and alphabetically by title within each name, followed by Unidentified and Other Papers.
  Scope and Contents
  Composers represented in this series include many musicians associated with the British and Hanoverian courts. Among earlier materials originating in England is music by Johann Christian Bach and musicians of his circle, including Montague Corri, Charles Egan, Charles Frederick Horn, Charles Edward Horn, Joseph Kemp, Augustus Frederic Christopher Kollmann, Frederick Nicolay, Christopher Papendiek, Johann Samuel Schroeter, William Southbrook, and Charles Wesley. Hanoverian musicians include Georg von Bredow, Julius Gerold, Andreas Hammerschmidt, Heinrich Heidrich, August Lang, and Wilhelm Westmayer. Also present are many works and arrangements by military band musicians. Manuscripts of Georg V include drafts and fair copies of his music, lists of his works, and drafts for a theoretical work, Ideen und Betrachtungen über die Eigenschaften der Musik. Composers such as Beethoven, Clementi, Haydn, Mozart, Rossini, Johann Strauss, Sr., Weber, Berlioz and Mendelssohn are represented by early printed editions or copyist's manuscripts. Early editions of parts for Haydn symphonies are present, some with manuscript cancels or additions in unidentified hands. Some composers in this series may also be found in Series III, Duke of Cumberland's Band Archive, and Series IV. Hanover Liturgical Manuscripts.
  While some marks of provenance of individual items are indicated in folder notes, the collection contains extensive additional evidence of ownership and use, including control signatures of composers and publishers indicating ownership of copyright, manuscript inscriptions and performance annotations, manuscript music cancels and additions, personalized bindings, presentation bindings, and dedication inscriptions and related correspondence. Most evidence of provenance relates to Ernest Augustus, Princess Augusta, Princess Amelia, and Georg V. Also present is music dedicated to Queen Charlotte, George IV, Queen Victoria, Ernst August (1845-1923), the Duke of Braunschweig and Lüneburg, and Wilhelm I, King of Prussia.
  Following materials organized by name is music by unidentified composers, subarranged for voice, keyboard, and instrumental ensemble. A small amount of other papers contains printed ephemera relating to concerts, church services, and other events; manuscript notes; and detached shelf mark labels and other binding fragments.
  - Abel, Johann Leopold, 1795-1871
    - Six Popular German Ballads. Score. Print (London: for author by Cramer, Addison & Beale), undated; (2 copies) (Box 877)
  - Abingdon, Willoughby Bertie, Earl of, 1740-1799
    - Twenty-One Vocal Pieces For several Voices with a Piano Forte Accompaniment.... Score. Print (London: Monzani), 1797 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Signed: T. Monzani
  - Abrams, Harriett, 1760-1825
    - [Songs]. Score. Print (no publisher name), 1803; (2 copies) (Box 340)
      Ex libris: Comte de Caumont
  - Abt, Franz, 1819-1885
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 341)
  - Adam, Adolphe, 1803-1856
    - Music. Manuscript, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adolphus, Duke of Cambridge, 1774-1850
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alexandra Josiphowna, Grand Duchess of Russia, 1830-1911
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alfieri, Pietro, 1801-1863
    - Music. Print, typeset, 1842-1851, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aline
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Allegri, Gregorio, 1582-1652
    - Music. Manuscript and print, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Related Archival Materials note
      Includes: Bai, Tommaso
  - Ander, Alois
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 342)
  - André, Anton
    - Lieder und Gesänge mit Begleitung des Piano-Forte...Erstes Heft. Score. Print, lithograph (Offenbach: Johann André), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Angely, Louis, 1787-1835
    - Sieben Mädchen in Uniform: Vaudeville in einem Aufzuge.... Arranged by Heinrich Aloys Praeger. Vocal score. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Signed by Princess Augusta
  - Anger, Louis
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 343)
  - Antony, Joseph, 1790-1837
    - Archäologisch-liturgisches Lehrbuch des Gregorianischen Kirchengesanges. Print, typeset (Münster: Coppenrath), 1829 (Box 344)
  - Arditi, Luigi, 1822-1903
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Arne, Thomas Augustine, 1710-1778
    - [Alfred. Rule, Britannia]. Arranged for voice and piano. Score. Manuscript, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Arnim, Charles, Baron
    - A Selection of German National Melodies...Volume 1. Score. Print (London: Goulding, D'Almaine, Potter & Co.), 1816? (Box 878)
  - Arnold, F. W.
    - Music. Print, 1841? (Box 2, Folder 13)
      With: autograph letter, signed, to Ernest Augustus (1771-1851)
  - Arnold, Samuel, 1740-1802
    - Cathedral Music. 3 volumes. Score. Print (London: D'Almaine), 1843? (Box 879, Box 880, Box 881)
    - [Inkle and Yarico]. Vocal score. Print (London: Longman & Broderip), undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Asche, Carl
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Asche, W.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 882)
  - Asioli, Bonifazio, 1769-1832
    - [Duets, voice]. Six Duetts, Three for Two Sopranos, and Three for a Soprano & Tenor, with an Accompaniment for a Piano Forte.... Score. Print (London: Birchall), circa 1797? (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Astorga, Emanuele, barone d', b. 1680.
    - Music. Print, 1864? (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Music. Print, 1864? (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Attwood, Thomas, 1765-1838
    - [The Mouth of the Nile]. Vocal score. Print (London: Goulding Phipps & d'Almaine), undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
      Signed by the composer
    - [Sonatas, piano, op. 2]. Three Sonatas for the Piano Forte.... Print (London: Longman & Broderip), undated (Box 345)
  - Auber, D. F. E. Daniel François Esprit), 1782-1871
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 346)
  - Augusta Sophia, Princess, daughter of George III, King of Great Britain, 1768-1840
    - A Slow March and Quick Step and a German Air. For woodwinds and brass. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 4 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 tpt, trbn). Manuscript, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Aylward, Theodore, 1730-1801
    - [Canzonets, sopranos (2)]. Eight Canzonets for Two Soprano Voices. Score. Print (London: for author), undated; (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 24)
      Dedication to Princess Augusta and Princess Elizabeth
  - Bach, Johann Christian, 1735-1782
    See also: Music Collections/Manuscript Music Books/Unidentified
    See also: Music Collections/Bound Collections
    - [Concertos, harpsichord, string orchestra, W. C 49-54]. Six Concerti pour le Clavecin, Deux Violons & une Violoncelle.... Op. 1. Parts (hpd, 2 vn). Print (London: Bremner), undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - [Marches]. Bach's Two Favorite Marches. For keyboard and flute or violin, or 2 flutes. Score. Print (London: J. Dale), undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - [Sonatas]. Print, undated (Box 347)
      Bound collection: [Sonatas, keyboard instrument, W. A 1-6] (London: Bremner); [Sonatas, violin, keyboard instrument, W. B 2-7] (London: Welcker); [Sonatas, flute, keyboard instrument, W. B 10-15] (London: Welcker); [Sonatas, keyboard instrument, W. A 7-12] (London: Welcker)
      Some manuscript fingerings and other annotations
      Book-binder's title, in manuscript: Bach's Sonatas, Harpsichord
  - Bach, Johann Christoph, 1642-1703
    - [Motets]. Neun Motetten für Singchöre von Johann Christoph Bach und Johann Michael Bach. Ites-IIItes Heft. Score. Print (Leipzig: Hofmeister), undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Bach, Johann Michael, 1648-1694
    See: Bach, Johann Christoph, 1642-1703
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
    - Music. Print, 1855, undated (Box 6-10, Folder 28-40)
    - [Works]. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), [1851-1897?] (Box 348-393)
      46 volumes, numbered on spine 1-4, 5I, 5II, 6-45
      Book-binder's title: Bach's Werke
    - [Works]. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), 1896 (Box 394)
      Paperbound
  - Bai, Tommaso, 1650-1714
    See: Allegri, Gregorio, 1582-1652
  - Baker, T.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Balfe, M. W. (Michael William), 1808-1870
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Baligand, Max von
    - Music. Manuscript, 1865 May 27 (Box 395)
  - Barthélemon, F.-H. (François-Hippolyte), 1741-1808
    - [Jefte in Masfa]. Selections from the Oratorio Jefte in Masfa.... Vocal score. Print (London: Clement, Collard & Collard), undated (Box 396)
    - [Jefte in Masfa]. Overtura di Jefte in Masfa. Parts (2 fl, vn, va, vc). Print, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Barthelemon, Mary, 1749-1799
    - An ode on the late providential preservation of our Most Gracious Sovereign.... Op. 5. Print (London: Culliford, Rolf, & Barrow), circa 1795 (Box 397)
  - Battye, Mrs.
    - Five Sacred Melodies, Composed for the Piano Forte, and dedicated...to Her Royal Highness The Princess Augusta.... Songs. Score. Print (London: T. Welsh), undated; (4 copies) (Box 11, Folder 44)
      Each copy annotated: JLB
  - Bauerhahn, Carl
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Bausset, Alexandre de
    - Six Rondes pour deux et trois Voix avec Accompagnement de Piano Forte....Score. Print (London: author), undated (Box 11, Folder 46)
      Signed by composer
  - Bazzini, Antonio, 1818-1897
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 398)
  - Beck, J.
    - Music. Manuscript, 1860, undated (Box 11-12, Folder 47-50)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827
    - [Allemandes]. 12 Allemande pour le Pianoforte.... Print (Leipzig: Peters), undated (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - [Schottische Lieder, op. 108]. Schottishe lieder.... Heft I-III. Scores. Print (Berlin: Schlesinger), undated (Box 399)
      Bound collection
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 8, op. 13, C minor]. Grande Sonate Pathetique.... Print (Bonn: N. Simrock), undated (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - [Sonatas, piano, no. 17, op. 31, no. 2, D minor]. Trois Sonates pour le Piano-forte...Oeuvre 31 Liv. 2. Print (Paris: H. Simrock), undated (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - [Works]. Beethovens Werke...Serie 12. Für Pianoforte und Violine. Part (vn). Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf und Härtel), undated (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Bellini, Vincenzo, 1801-1835
    - Norma.... Vocal score. Print (Milan: Ricordi), undated (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - I Puritani...für die deutsche Bühne bearbeitet von dem Freiherrn von Lichtenstein. Vocal score. Print (Mainz and Antwerp: B. Schott's sons), circa 1838? (Box 400)
      Label on cover: Musik-Leih-Institut von C. Bachmann in Hannover
  - Beneken, Friedrich Burchard, 1760-1818
    - Melodieen zu den Liedern für Volksschulen. Dritte Ausgabe. Print, typeset (Hanover: bey den Gebrüdern Hahn), 1809 (Box 401)
  - Bennett, Thomas
    - Sacred Melodies: A collection of Psalms and Hymns.... Part 1-4. Third edition. Print (London: Latour), undated (Box 402)
      Cover annotated: Princess Augusta 1829
  - Bennett, William Sterndale, Sir, 1816-1875
    - Music. Print, typeset, 1863 (Box 403)
  - Benz, J. B.
    - Music. Print, typeset, 1864 (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - Berendt, Nicolai
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 404)
  - Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869
    - Grande Messe des morts.... Score. Print (Paris: Schlesinger), undated; (2 copies) (Box 13-14, Folder 57-58)
    - [Te Deum, op. 22]. Te Deum.... Score. Print (Paris: Brandus, Dufour et cie), 1855 (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - Beyer, Hermann
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Beyer, Rudolph
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 405)
  - Birchall, Robert, 1750- 1819
    - A Catalogue of Instrumental and Vocal Music.... Print, typeset (London: Sampson Low), 1800 (Box 15, Folder 61)
  - Birkler
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - Bishop, Henry R. (Henry Rowley), Sir, 1786-1855
    - Mourn the Bright Rose: A Hebrew Dirge.... Score. Print (London: Goulding, D'Almaine, Potter & Co), undated (Box 15, Folder 63)
    - A Selection of Irish Melodies.... 9th Number. Score. Print (London: J. Power), undated (Box 406)
      Cover annotated: HRH Princess Augusta
    - A Selection of Popular National Airs.... Sixth Number. Score. Print (London: J. Power), undated (Box 407)
    - Twelve Corales.... Score. Print (London: Lonsdale), undated (Box 408)
  - Bland, John, ca. 1750-ca. 1840
    - The Ladies Collection of Catches, Glees, Canons.... No.1-6. Score. Print (London: Birchall), circa 1800 (Box 409-410)
      Spine: monogram of Princess Augusta
      Book-binder's label: Wilson
  - Blandford, Marquess of
    - Arie...Con Accompagnamento Composte Da'l Marchese di Blandford. Score. Print (no publisher), undated (Box 411)
    - Rule Britannia, Done into Latin Verse.... Score. Print (L. Pleydell Bouverie), undated (Box 15, Folder 64)
  - Blangini, Felice, 1781-1841
    - [Duets, voices]. Duett von Blangini gesungen von Madame Seidler und Herrn Haizinger in der Oper Der Barbier von Sevilla. Score. Print (Berlin: Trautwein), undated (Box 15, Folder 65)
    - [Duets, voices]. Huit Nouveaux Nocturnes Italiens à deux voix.... Score. Print (Berlin: Lischke), undated (Box 15, Folder 66)
    - [Songs]. Samlung Italiänischer und Deutscher Lieder.... Parte II. Score. Print (Vienna: Artaria), undated (Box 15, Folder 67)
  - Blockley, John
    - The Sabbath Minstrel.... Score. Print (London: Chappell), undated (Box 412)
  - Blumenstengel, A.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 883)
  - Boccherini, Luigi, 1743-1805
    - [Sonatas, violin, piano, G. 25-30]. Six Sonatas for the Harpsichord or Piano-Forte With an Accompaniment for a violin or German Flute.... Op. 3. Part (hpd). Print (London: Longman, Lukey & Co.), undated (Box 15, Folder 68)
      Missing pages 1-2, 15-26, 39-40
  - Bochsa, Robert Nicolas Charles, 1789-1856
    - A New and Improved Method of Instruction for the Harp.... Print (London: Chappell & Co.), undated (Box 16, Folder 69)
  - Bödecker, L.
    - Music. Manuscript, 1878 (Box 16, Folder 70)
  - Böhme, H.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 16, Folder 71)
  - Böhmer, Carl
    - Meerkönig und sein Liebchen.... Arranged by F. H. Reissiger. Vocal score. Print (Berlin: Westphal), undated (Box 16, Folder 72)
  - Böhner, Johann Ludwig, 1787-1860
    - Music. Print, lithograph, undated (Box 17, Folder 73)
  - Börner, Alexander
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 17, Folder 74)
  - Boieldieu, François Adrien, 1775-1834
    - La dame blanche.... Arranged by Carl Zulehner. Vocal score. Print (Bonn and Cologne: N. Simrock), circa 1825 (Box 413)
  - Bossi, Cesare, 1773-1802
    - Le Melange: the Favorite Pas de Trois...Arranged for the Piano Forte. No.19. Print (London: L. Lavenu), undated (Box 17, Folder 75)
  - Bott, J. J. (Jean Joseph), 1826-1895
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 414)
  - Bottger, G.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 17, Folder 76)
  - Boyce, William, 1711-1779
    - Fifteen Anthems, together with a Te Deum, and Jubilate.... Score. Print (London: for the author's widow and family), 1780 (Box 415)
      Ex libris: Edm.d T. Warren Horne Esq.r
      Other ownership inscriptions
    - Cathedral Music.... Volumes 1-3. Score. Print (London: for the editor), 1760-1773 (Box 416-418)
  - Braasch, Hinrich
    - Music. Manuscript, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 77)
  - Brackebusch, Anna
    - Music. Manuscript, 1868 (Box 17, Folder 78)
  - Braham, John, 1774-1856
    - [The cabinet]. The Favorite Bird Duet.... Vocal score. Print (London: J. Dale), undated (Box 17, Folder 79)
    - A Selection of Hebrew Melodies...by J. Brahama nd J. Nathan..... No. 1-2. Score. Print (London: Nathan), 1815 (Box 17-18, Folder 80-81)
      Signed by J. Nathan
      Annotated: Princess Augusta
  - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897
    - Geistliches Lied.... For chorus and piano. Score. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), undated (Box 18, Folder 82)
    - [Motets, mixed voices, op. 29]. 2 Motetten.... No. 1-2. Score and parts (SATBB). Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), 1864? (Box 18, Folder 83)
    - [Psalm 23]. Der 23. Psalm.... For chorus and piano. Score and parts (SA). Print (Vienna: Spina), 1864? (Box 419)
  - Brand, Carl
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 18, Folder 84)
  - Brandes, Wilhelm
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 18, Folder 85)
      With: autograph letter signed, from Brandes to Ernest Augustus (1771-1851)
  - Branzoli, Giuseppe, 1835-1909
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 18, Folder 86)
  - Bratfisch, A.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 18, Folder 87)
  - Braune, F. W. Otto
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 420)
  - Bredow, Georg von
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 421-422)
  - Brenner, Louis de
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 423)
  - Brooks, James, ca. 1757-1819
    - [English ballads]. Twelve English Ballads adapted for the Piano Forte, & Harp with an Accompaniment...for a Flute or Violin.... Score and part (vn or fl). Print (London: author), undated (Box 19, Folder 88)
  - Brosang, H.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 424)
  - Bruguier, D.
    - A Military Divertimento.... Op. 22. Parts (pf, hp, fl, 2 hn). Print (London: author), undated; (4 copies) (Box 19, Folder 89)
      Dedication to Princess Augusta
    - When in Death You Recline.... Song. Score. Print (London: for author), undated (Box 19, Folder 90)
  - Brune, Hermann
    - Music. Print, lithograph, undated (Box 19, Folder 91)
  - Buckholz
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 19, Folder 92)
  - Bunsen
    - Music. Manuscript, 1827? (Box 19, Folder 93)
      With: autograph letter, signed, from the composer to "Königliche Hoheit," 1827
  - Busby, Thomas, 1754-1838
    - [Joanna of Montfoucon]. The Music in the Dramatic Romance of Joanna.... Score. Print (London: Goulding, Phipps & D'Almaine), undated (Box 20, Folder 94)
  - Cahusac, William, 1770-after 1828
    - [Duets, voices]. Six Italian Duettinos and Two Canzonettas with an Accompaniment for the Piano Forte.... Op. 1. Score. Print (London: author), undated (Box 20, Folder 95)
  - Caldara, Antonio, 1670-1736
    - Music. Print, 1840 (Box 20, Folder 96-97)
  - Calkin, James, 1786-1862
    - The Dove: A sequent to the justly admired Song of The Thorn.... Score. Print (by subscription), undated; (2 copies) (Box 21, Folder 98)
  - Callcott, John Wall, 1766-1821
    - [Songs]. A Collection of Four Songs.... Score. Print (London: for the author), 1804 March (Box 21, Folder 99)
  - Callcott, William H. (William Hutchins), 1807-1882
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 21, Folder 100)
  - Camidge, Matthew, 1764?-1844
    - [Sonatas, violin, violoncello, piano]. Three Sonatas for the Piano-Forte or Harpsichord with Accompaniments for a Violin & Violoncello.... Parts (vn, vc, pf). Print (London: Preston & Son), undated (Box 21, Folder 101)
  - Campagnoli, Bartolomeo, 1751-1827
    - Nouvelle Méthode de la Mécanique Progressive du Jeu de Violon...Oeuvre 21. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), undated; (3 copies) (Box 425-427)
      1 copy dated 1823 on cover
  - Campbell, Caroline, 18th cent.
    - Music's sweet Measure...by Caroline Honoria Campell.... Song. Score. Print (London: Duff), undated; (5 copies) (Box 21, Folder 102)
  - Cantone, Carlo, 18th cent.
    - [Sonatas, violin, keyboard]. Sei Sonate per il cembalo con accompagnamento di Violino.... Parts (kbd, vn, b). Print (Turin?), 1778? (Box 21, Folder 103)
  - Carafa, Michele, 1787-1872
    - Le solitaire.... Vocal score. Print (Mainz: B. Schott Sons), 1823? (Box 428)
      Annotated: H. R. H. Pss. Augusta
  - Cardon, Jean-Baptiste, 1760-1803
    - Ah vous dirai je maman, with variations, pour la harp par Cardon Fils. Print (London: Chappell & Co.), undated (Box 22, Folder 104)
      Manuscript fingering
  - Carnaby, William, 1772-1839
    See: Horn, Charles Frederick, 1762-1830
  - Chambers, Miss (Marianne), fl. 1799-1811
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 429)
  - Cherubini, Luigi, 1760-1842
    - [Chant sur la mort de Haydn]. Chant sur la mort de Joseph Hayd'n.... Arranged for piano. Print, typeset (Berlin: Schlesinger), undated (Box 22, Folder 105)
      Book-seller's label: B. Schott, Mainz
  - Christoph, W.
    - Music. Manuscript, undated (Box 22, Folder 106-107)
  - Chrysander, Friedrich, 1826-1901
    - [Georg Friedrich Händel]. G. F. Händel.... Volumes 1-2. Biography. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), 1858-1860 (Box 430-431)
    - Jahrbücher für musikalische Wissenschaft. Print (Leipzig: Breitkopf & Härtel), 1863 (Box 432)
      Annotated: Kronprinz von Hannover
    - Music. Print, 1870 (Box 22, Folder 108)
  - Cimarosa, Domenico, 1749-1801
    - [La löcandiera. Excerpt]. Duetto Con quelle tue manine.... Opera. Score. Print (London: Longman & Broderip), 1788 (Box 22, Folder 109)
  - Clarke-Whitfeld, John, 1770-1836
    - The Beauties of Purcell.... Score. Print (London: Birchall), 1808? (Box 23, Folder 110)
    - Twelve Favorite Anthems.... Volume 3. Score. Print (London: Preston), undated (Box 433)
    - Fifteen Favorite Anthems.... Volumes 1-2. Score. Print (London: Birchall), undated (Box 434-435)
  - Clementi, Muzio, 1752-1832
    - [Sonata, piano, op. 16, D major]. La Chasse Pour Le Clavecin ou Forte Piano.... Print (London: Longman, Clementi & Co.), undated (Box 23, Folder 111)
    - [Sonata, piano, op. 16, D major]. La Chasse Pour Le Clavecin ou Forte Piano.... Print (London: Longman and Broderip), undated (Box 23, Folder 112)
      Missing pages 3-4 and 9
    - [Sonatas, piano, op. 23]. Three Sonatas for the Pianoforte or Harpsichord.... Manuscript, undated (Box 23, Folder 113)
    - [Sonatas, piano, op. 25]. Sonatas. Six Sonatas for the Piano-Forte.... Print (London: J. Dale), undated (Box 23, Folder 114)
    - [Sonatas and duet, op. 12]. Four Sonatas for the Piano Forte and One Duett for two Piano Fortes.... Print (London: J. Preston), undated (Box 24, Folder 115)
  - Collier, John
    - [La chasse. Overture]. Ouverture La Chasse.... By N. A. Shaffner; arranged for military band by Collier. Parts (2 fl, 6 cl, 2 hn, 2 spt (1 part), tpt, trbn). Print (London: W. Millhouse), undated (Box 24, Folder 116)
      Original folder: not present; music numbered 19 and 93A
    - [Concertante]. A Concertante for two tertio flutes obligato.... By François Devienne; arranged for military band by Collier. Parts (2 fl, 6 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt, trbn). Print (London: W. Milhouse), undated (Box 24, Folder 117)
    - [Concertante]. Concertant. By Adelbert Gyrowetz; arranged for band by Collier. Parts (2 fl, 2 ob, 4 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt, trbn). Manuscript, undated (Box 24-25, Folder 118-119)
      Original folder: not present; music numbered 26 and177
    - Three Pieces of Harmony.... By Kromer; arranged for military band by Collier. Parts (2 fl, 6 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt, trbn). Print (London: W. Milhouse), undated (Box 25, Folder 120)
    - The Prince Regents March, for A Military Band.... Parts (2 fl (1 part), 6 cl (3 parts), 2 bn (1 part), spt and trbn (1 part), 2 hn (1 part), 3 tpt (2 parts)). Print (London: W. Milhouse), undated (Box 25, Folder 121)
      Original folder: not present; music numbered 20
    - [Waltzes]. Six Waltzes Composed Expressly for the Congress at Vienna.... Set 2. Parts (2 fl, 6 cl, 2 bn, spt, 2 hn, tpt, trbn). Print (London: W. Milhouse), undated (Box 25, Folder 122)
      Original folder: not present; music numbered 18
  - Commer, Franz, 1813-1887
    - Music. Print, 1857-1863, undated (Box 25-29, Folder 123-135)
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 436-438)
  - Coninx, L.
    - Music. Print, undated (Box 439)